# Ethan J. Reimer

ereimer18@georgefox.edu | (253) 709-0006 | linkedin.com/in/ethanreimer/ | www.ethanreimer.com/

## **Professional Summary**

Highly motivated computer science major with a focus in cybersecurity. A devoted team member with leadership skills, dedication and experience working with a variety of groups and cultures. Able to diligently perform a wide variety of tasks with key organizational skills and close attention to detail. Curious with a strong desire to learn and take on projects offering new skills.

### **Education**

# George Fox University, Newberg, OR

Expected April 2022

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Cyber Security | GPA: 3.64

Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Digital Logic, Software Engineering, Computer Security and Digital Forensics, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Analysis of Algorithms, Emerging Mobile Technologies, Database Systems, Data Communications and Networks, Computer Architecture/Assembly Languages, Servant Engineering, Operating Systems, Network Administration, Secure Software, Advanced Security, Structures of Programming Languages, Parallel and Distributed Computing, Web Development, Senior Design

#### **Technical Skills**

- Python
- Java
- C/C++
- C#
- Scala
- HTML

- CSS
- JavaScript
- Git
- Docker
- SQL
- Linux

- Virtual Machines
- Scripting
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Cybersecurity

## **Collegiate Projects**

- Senior Design HoloLens Augmented Reality Development (current): in conjunction with Daimler Trucks, my senior-design team is developing an Augmented Reality application for a Microsoft HoloLens using Unity and Microsoft's Mixed Reality Took Kit to provide a hands-free holographic solution for the intake process.
- Chess: Object-Oriented implementation of a command-line driven chess game.
- Servant Engineering Haptic Feedback Device: a haptic feedback device to aid visually impaired students in understanding a graphical image. My particular focus was in developing a color tracking program utilizing computer vision.
- Magic Mirror IoT Device: configured and built a "magic mirror" smart device, consisting of a pi-driven monitor behind a two-way mirror that displayed modules such as the weather and notifications.
- Movie Database: parsed old HTML and XML files of movies, actors, studios, directors and more and created a PostgreSQL database containing the valid data.
- **Networking RFP:** drafted a bid in response to a hypothetical business Request for Proposal in my Data Communications and Networking course. Researched networking equipment and protocols necessary to put together a plan to restore a company to working order and improve network setup.

Course Scheduler: for my Software Engineering course, my class split into teams to create a proof-ofconcept course scheduling application to aid the George Fox academic departments in optimizing how
courses are scheduled with as few conflicts between departments as possible. My team worked on the
UI/UX aspect of the application, and we drafted several design options inspired by interviews with
several faculty. My specific role was to draft a test matrix to run tests on the UI portion of the
application. The development process focused on working with clients and using scrum and agile
development techniques.

# **Work Experience**

Barista, Chapters Books and Coffee, Newberg, ORAug 2021-presentDough Roller, Abby's Legendary Pizza, Newberg, ORJune 2021-Aug 2021Retail Associate, Lowes, Federal Way, WAJune 2020-Aug 2020Amazon Warehouse Associate, Amazon, Kent, WAMay 2019-July 2019

### **Contests**

- National Cyber League
  - Spring 2021
  - o Fall 2021

### **Volunteer Experience**

**ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest,** 2018: volunteered to help run the Oregon ACM ICPC hosted by George Fox University; volunteered for the high school version the following year.